<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<race name="Sporlings">
    <description>Creatures of the undergrowth, born from the mycelial network that binds the forest together.</description>
    <traits>
        <trait name="Fungal Fortitude">
            <description>Advantage on saving throws against poison and disease.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Nature's Embrace">
            <description>Proficient in the Nature skill.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Spore Cloud">
            <description>As an action, you can release a cloud of non-magical spores in a 15-foot radius. Creatures in the area must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier) or become poisoned for 1 minute. This ability recharges after a short or long rest.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Symbiotic Connection">
            <description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to find food and water in natural environments.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Mycelial Rest">
            <description>Instead of sleeping, Sporlings connect to the mycelium network to rejuvenate. This process takes 1 hour for a short rest and 2 hours for a long rest.</description>
        </trait>
    </traits>
    <physicalDescription>
        <appearance>Resemble humanoid mushrooms with varying degrees of sentience. Colors range from vibrant greens and browns to more subdued grays and whites.</appearance>
        <size>Typically smaller than humans, comparable to halflings or gnomes.</size>
        <speed>25 feet</speed>
        <height>3'6" to 4'6"</height>
        <weight>40-60 lbs</weight>
        <lifespan>150-200 years</lifespan>
    </physicalDescription>
    <languages>
        <language>Common</language>
        <language>Sylvan</language>
        <language>Mycelian</language>
    </languages>
    <equipment>
        <item>Spore Pouch: A small pouch containing dried spores that can be used to create a distracting cloud or to enhance natural camouflage.</item>
    </equipment>
    <suggestedBackgrounds>
        <background>Hermit: Many Sporelings live solitary lives, cultivating their own patches of mushrooms.</background>
        <background>Outlander: Some Sporelings are wanderers, exploring the natural world and forging connections with other creatures.</background>
        <background>Folk Hero: Sporelings who champion the rights of nature and protect the environment.</background>
    </suggestedBackgrounds>
    <roleplayingNotes>
        <note>Sporelings are a young race, still developing their own culture and society.</note>
        <note>They have a deep connection to nature and often feel a kinship with plants and animals.</note>
        <note>Many Sporelings are wary of other races, especially those who hunt or consume mushrooms.</note>
        <note>Some Sporlings may have unique abilities based on the type of mushroom they originated from, such as the ability to produce glowing spores or create illusions.</note>
    </roleplayingNotes>
</race>
