<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<race name="Kyubi">
    <description>A cunning and agile people, deeply connected to the sea and the rhythm of the tides, known for their trickery, mysticism, and nomadic lifestyle.</description>
    <appearance>
        <form>Humanoid foxes with nine distinct tails. Tails covered in fur that varies in color based on environment. They walk upright on two legs, front paws resembling human hands.</form>
        <size>Medium</size>
        <speed>30 feet</speed>
        <lifespan>Long-lived, often exceeding 150 years.</lifespan>
    </appearance>
    <traits>
        <trait name="Cunning Action">
            <description>As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Fox's Cunning">
            <description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Nine-Tails">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can expend a number of hit dice (up to a maximum equal to your Constitution modifier) to regain hit points. You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this trait again.</description>
        </trait>
    </traits>
    <tailManeuvers>
        <maneuver name="Trip">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check contested by the target's Strength (Athletics) check. On a success, the target is knocked prone.</description>
        </maneuver>
        <maneuver name="Distract">
            <description>As a bonus action, you can create a flurry of distracting movements with your tails, forcing enemies within 5 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw or be disadvantaged on their next attack roll.</description>
        </maneuver>
        <maneuver name="Balance">
            <description>While moving, you can use your tails to maintain balance on difficult terrain, granting you advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks to maintain your balance.</description>
        </maneuver>
    </tailManeuvers>
    <languages>
        <language>Common</language>
        <language>Sylvan</language>
        <language>Thieves' Cant</language>
    </languages>
    <roleplayingNotes>
        <note>Playful and Mischievous: Nine-tailed Foxes are known for their playful and mischievous nature.</note>
        <note>Independent Spirits: They value their freedom and independence above all else.</note>
        <note>Skilled Hunters: They are skilled hunters and survivalists.</note>
        <note>Social: Despite their independent nature, Nine-tailed Foxes can form strong bonds within their clans.</note>
    </roleplayingNotes>
</race>
