<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<elements>
<info>
<name>Kyubi</name>
<update version="0.1.0">
<file name="race-kyubi.xml" url="https://example.com/race-kyubi.xml"/>
</update>
</info>
<element name="Kyubi" type="Race" source="Custom Source" id="ID_RACE_KYUBI">
<description>
<p class="flavor">Before the chilling touch of the Creeping Stillness, the Jade Coast was a vibrant tapestry of life, teeming with energy. The waves crashed against the shore, the air hummed with the songs of unseen creatures, and the land was lush and vibrant. In this vibrant ecosystem, the Kyubi thrived, a people deeply connected to the sea and the rhythm of the tides.</p>
<p>Known for their cunning and agility, the Kyubi were not just hunters; they were tricksters, mystics, and wanderers. They lived in hidden coves and grottoes, their homes adorned with seashells, coral, and the bones of mythical creatures. They were a playful and mischievous people, known for their elaborate pranks, their uncanny ability to disappear into the mist, and their mastery of illusion magic.</p>
<p>The Kyubi were a nomadic people, drawn to the allure of the unknown. They roamed the coast, exploring hidden coves, seeking out rare treasures, and sharing stories around crackling campfires. They were skilled navigators, their ships adorned with intricate carvings and mystical symbols. They were known to trade with distant lands, bringing back exotic goods and weaving tales of their adventures.</p>
<p>But the Kyubi were more than just explorers. They were masters of disguise, able to blend seamlessly into any crowd, their nine tails a blur of motion as they navigated bustling marketplaces and treacherous jungles. They were tricksters and illusionists, capable of creating mesmerizing displays of light and shadow, confounding their enemies and delighting their friends.</p>
</description>
<sheet display="false"/>
<setters>
<set name="appearance" type="form">Humanoid foxes with nine distinct tails.</set>
<set name="appearance" type="size">Medium</set>
<set name="speed" modifier="base">30 feet</set>
<set name="lifespan">Long-lived, often exceeding 150 years.</set>
</setters>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CUNNING_ACTION"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FOX_CUNNING"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_NINE_TAILS"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_TAIL_MANEUVERS"/>
<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON"/>
<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN"/>
<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_THIEVES_CANT"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Cunning Action" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Source" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CUNNING_ACTION">
<description>
<p>As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>As a bonus action, you can take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
<element name="Fox's Cunning" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Source" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FOX_CUNNING">
<description>
<p>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
<element name="Nine-Tails" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Source" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_NINE_TAILS">
<description>
<p>As a bonus action, you can expend a number of hit dice (up to a maximum equal to your Constitution modifier) to regain hit points. You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this trait again.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Regain hit points by expending hit dice.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
<element name="Tail Maneuvers" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Source" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_TAIL_MANEUVERS">
<description>
<p>As a bonus action, you can perform various maneuvers with your tails.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Perform maneuvers such as Trip, Distract, and Balance.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
</elements>
