<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<elements>
<info>
<name>Metalborn</name>
<update version="0.1.0">
<file name="race-metalborn.xml" url="https://example.com/race-metalborn.xml"/>
</update>
</info>
<element name="Metalborn" type="Race" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_RACE_METALBORN">
<description>
<p class="flavor">The caravan, led by the seasoned merchant Alvorin, was crossing the Jade Plains, the shimmering emerald grassland stretching as far as the eye could see. They were not on the established trade routes, seeking a shortcut to reach the bustling city of Valoria. As they ventured deeper into the plains, an unsettling calm descended upon them. The vibrant hues of the Jade Plains seemed to fade, replaced by an eerie stillness. Suddenly, from the heart of a shimmering emerald grove, emerged a group of figures, their skin gleaming like polished metal, their eyes radiating an otherworldly light. These were the Metalborn, guardians of the Jade Plains, and they were not pleased with the unforeseen intrusion.</p>
<p class="indent">Alvorin, a man who had faced many dangers in his travels, recognized the threat. These were no ordinary beings. Their strength was evident in their every movement, and their aura exuded an almost divine power. He knew then that their journey would be far more perilous than he had ever imagined.</p>
<p class="indent">The Metalborn, driven by a deep sense of duty and a fierce loyalty to the Jade Plains, challenged the caravan. A fierce battle ensued, the merchants struggling against the overwhelming power of the Metalborn. But as the fight raged, Alvorin noticed something unexpected – a flicker of hesitation in the eyes of one of the Metalborn warriors. This warrior, unlike the others, seemed conflicted, his blows less forceful, his gaze filled with a strange uncertainty.</p>
<p class="indent">This encounter with the Metalborn left a profound impact on Alvorin. He realized that these beings were not merely guardians, but individuals with their own hopes, fears, and desires. He also understood that the Jade Plains held secrets far deeper than he had initially imagined, secrets intertwined with the very essence of the Metalborn themselves.</p>
<h4>APPEARANCE</h4>
<p>Metalborn resemble humanoid beings with skin that appears to be made of polished metal. The texture and color of their skin vary depending on their "metal type."</p>
<h4>METAL TYPES</h4>
<ul class="unstyled">
<li><strong>Copper:</strong> Copper Metalborn have warm, reddish-brown skin that glows faintly. They often have intricate copper-colored hair and eyes that shift between shades of green and blue.</li>
<li><strong>Gold:</strong> Gold Metalborn have skin that shines with a golden luster. They typically have flowing, golden hair and piercing golden eyes.</li>
<li><strong>Iron:</strong> Iron Metalborn have a tough, gray-black skin that is resistant to damage. They often have short, dark hair and piercing black eyes.</li>
<li><strong>Platinum:</strong> Platinum Metalborn have skin that is smooth and silvery-white. They often have silvery-white hair and eyes that seem to reflect the light.</li>
</ul>
<h4>SOCIETY</h4>
<p>Metalborn typically live in small, close-knit communities, often located near sources of valuable metals. They may inhabit fortified settlements in the Iron Peaks or hidden caverns rich in minerals.</p>
<p>Metalborn tend to be pragmatic and logical, valuing strength, resilience, and order. They prioritize duty, honor, and the protection of their people and their home.</p>
<h4>LIFESPAN</h4>
<p>Metalborn live between 500 to 1000 years.</p>
</description>
<sheet display="false"/>
<setters>
<set name="size">Medium</set>
<set name="speed">30 feet</set>
<set name="lifespan">500-1000 years</set>
</setters>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALBORN_RESILIENCE"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALLIC_FORM"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALLIC_TOUCH"/>
<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON"/>
<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_OTHER"/>
<select type="Sub Race" name="Metalborn Subrace" supports="Metalborn" optional="true"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Metalborn Resilience" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALBORN_RESILIENCE">
<description>
<p>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons.</description>
</sheet>
<rules>
<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NONMAGICAL"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Metallic Form" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALLIC_FORM">
<description>
<p>As an action, you can temporarily harden your skin, increasing your AC by 1 for 1 minute.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>As an action, you can temporarily harden your skin, increasing your AC by 1 for 1 minute.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
<element name="Metallic Touch" type="Racial Trait" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_METALLIC_TOUCH">
<description>
<p>You can use your hands to manipulate metal objects as if you were using tools.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>You can use your hands to manipulate metal objects as if you were using tools.</description>
</sheet>
<rules/>
</element>
<element name="Copper Metalborn" type="Subrace" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_SUBRACE_COPPER_METALBORN">
<description>
<p>Copper Metalborn can conduct electricity and their fists can be used as improvised bludgeoning weapons that deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Copper Metalborn can conduct electricity.</description>
<description>Natural Weapon: Their fists can be used as improvised bludgeoning weapons that deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage.</description>
</sheet>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CONDUCTIVITY"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_NATURAL_WEAPON"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Gold Metalborn" type="Subrace" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_SUBRACE_GOLD_METALBORN">
<description>
<p>Gold Metalborn can emit a soft, radiant glow that provides dim light in a 10-foot radius and have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Radiant Aura: The Gold Metalborn can emit a soft, radiant glow that provides dim light in a 10-foot radius.</description>
<description>Charismatic Presence: Gold Metalborn have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</description>
</sheet>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_RADIANT_AURA"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHARISMATIC_PRESENCE"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Iron Metalborn" type="Subrace" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_SUBRACE_IRON_METALBORN">
<description>
<p>Iron Metalborn have advantage on Constitution saving throws and can ignore the effects of one attack that would otherwise reduce them to 0 hit points once per long rest.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Iron Will: Advantage on Constitution saving throws.</description>
<description>Unbreakable Resolve: Once per long rest, the Iron Metalborn can ignore the effects of one attack that would otherwise reduce them to 0 hit points.</description>
</sheet>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_IRON_WILL"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_UNBREAKABLE_RESOLVE"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Platinum Metalborn" type="Subrace" source="Custom Lore" id="ID_SUBRACE_PLATINUM_METALBORN">
<description>
<p>Platinum Metalborn can become partially ethereal for 1 round, immune to nonmagical attacks, and have advantage on saving throws against psychic damage.</p>
</description>
<sheet>
<description>Ethereal Form: As a bonus action, the Platinum Metalborn can become partially ethereal for 1 round.</description>
<description>Psychic Resistance: Advantage on saving throws against psychic damage.</description>
</sheet>
<rules>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ETHEREAL_FORM"/>
<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_PSYCHIC_RESISTANCE"/>
</rules>
</element>
<element name="Metalborn Subrace" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_METALBORN_SUBRACE"/>
</elements>
