<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<class name="Warden of the Wild">
    <description>Guardians of nature, attuned to the elemental forces that shape the world.</description>
    <traits>
        <trait name="Elemental Attunement">
            <description>Choose an element (Earth, Fire, Water, or Air) and gain unique abilities and resistances.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Wild Shape">
            <description>Transform parts of your body into your chosen element, becoming more attuned to the natural world.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Nature's Guidance">
            <description>You have a deep connection to nature, granting you advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks.</description>
        </trait>
        <trait name="Elemental Mastery">
            <description>You gain the power to cast spells from the Druid spell list, harnessing the magic of the elements.</description>
        </trait>
    </traits>
    <subclasses>
        <subclass name="Earth Warden">
            <description>Guardians of the deep earth, embodying resilience and steadfastness.</description>
            <levelAbilities>
                <ability level="3">Earthen Resilience: Resistance to bludgeoning damage. Earth Meld: Bonus action, meld into the earth, become invisible until end of next turn, advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</ability>
                <ability level="5">Tremorsense: Sense vibrations in the ground within 30 feet, detect creatures/objects moving through solid earth.</ability>
                <ability level="7">Stone's Embrace: When hit by an attack, use reaction to reduce damage by 1d8 + proficiency bonus.</ability>
                <ability level="9">Stone Shape: Cast Stone Shape 1/long rest.</ability>
            </levelAbilities>
        </subclass>
        <subclass name="Fire Warden">
            <description>With spirits ablaze, these wardens command the destructive and purifying power of fire.</description>
            <levelAbilities>
                <ability level="3">Burning Aura: Resistance to fire damage. Fiery Burst: Bonus action, unleash fiery burst, dealing fire damage to creatures within 5 feet.</ability>
                <ability level="5">Ignite: Cast Produce Flame cantrip at will.</ability>
                <ability level="7">Burning Hands: Cast Burning Hands 1/long rest.</ability>
                <ability level="9">Flame Blade: Cast Flame Blade 1/long rest.</ability>
            </levelAbilities>
        </subclass>
        <subclass name="Water Warden">
            <description>Adaptable and fluid, these wardens embody the ever-changing nature of water.</description>
            <levelAbilities>
                <ability level="3">Fluid Form: Resistance to cold damage, swimming speed = walking speed. Water Breathing: Breathe underwater indefinitely.</ability>
                <ability level="5">Shape Water: Cast Shape Water cantrip at will.</ability>
                <ability level="7">Water Whip: Create a whip of water, dealing cold damage.</ability>
                <ability level="9">Water Walk: Cast Water Walk 1/long rest.</ability>
            </levelAbilities>
        </subclass>
        <subclass name="Air Warden">
            <description>Free-spirited and swift, these wardens embody the untamed power of the wind.</description>
            <levelAbilities>
                <ability level="3">Wind's Embrace: Flying speed = walking speed. Gust of Wind: Bonus action, create gust, push creatures/objects away.</ability>
                <ability level="5">Zephyr's Shield: Reaction, create a shield of air, +2 to AC against one ranged attack.</ability>
                <ability level="7">Feather Fall: Cast Feather Fall 1/long rest.</ability>
                <ability level="9">Call Lightning: Cast Call Lightning 1/long rest.</ability>
            </levelAbilities>
        </subclass>
    </subclasses>
    <levelProgression>
        <level number="1" proficiency="+2">Wild Shape Beast Of The Land land creatures only small size</level>
        <level number="2" proficiency="+2">Natures Guidance Advantage on Wisdom (Survival) and Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</level>
        <level number="3" proficiency="+2">elemental attunement</level>
        <level number="4" proficiency="+2">as improvement 2pt in 1 score or 1pt in 2 scores or feat</level>
        <level number="5" proficiency="+3">-</level>
        <level number="6" proficiency="+3">Elemental Harmony: Gain proficiency in Nature skill or Survival skill</level>
        <level number="7" proficiency="+3">Elemental Sense: Gain advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks to notice environmental changes or hidden creatures.</level>
        <level number="8" proficiency="+3">as improvement 2pt in 1 score or 1pt in 2 scores or feat</level>
        <level number="9" proficiency="+4">-</level>
        <level number="10" proficiency="+4">Wild Shape Improvment Beasts of The Sea swiming and mediam creatures</level>
        <level number="11" proficiency="+4">Elemental Focus: Choose one element. When you use an action to cast a spell of your chosen element type, you can use a bonus action to gain advantage on the spell's attack roll or saving throw.</level>
        <level number="12" proficiency="+4">as improvment 2pt in 1 score or 1pt in 2 scores or feat</level>
        <level number="13" proficiency="+5">-</level>
        <level number="14" proficiency="+5">Elemental Defense: When you take damage from a source of your chosen element type, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by an amount equal to your Wisdom modifier.</level>
        <level number="15" proficiency="+5">-</level>
        <level number="16" proficiency="+5">as improvment 2pt in 1 score or 1pt in 2 scores or feat</level>
        <level number="17" proficiency="+6">-</level>
        <level number="18" proficiency="+6">Wild Shape Improvment Beasts of The Sky flying and larg creatures</level>
        <level number="19" proficiency="+6">-</level>
        <level number="20" proficiency="+6">as improvment 2pt in 1 score or 1pt in 2 scores or feat</level>
    </levelProgression>
</class>
